export const FINANCIALACCOUNTINGA2018 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A limitation to the use of accounting information is that",
A: "it is expressed in monetary terms only",
B: "it provides permanent records for all financial transactions",
C: "it distinguishes assets from liabilities",
D: "it determines the profitability of a business concern",
answer: "D. Profitability",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The petty cash book is used to record",
A: "cash discounts",
B: "credit sales",
C: "small payments",
D: "credit purchases",
answer: "B. Comparability",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Instructions given to a bank by a customer to receive or make payment on his behalf is",
A: "standing order",
B: "credit transfer",
C: "bank charges",
D: "uncredited cheques",
answer: "B. Discount allowed",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. A bank purchased a computer and debited the amount to purchases account. This is an error of",
A: "commission",
B: "principle",
C: "omission",
D: "original entry",
answer: "D. Purchase of fuel for vehicle",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. A summary account which contains in total the entries made in the personal ledgers and usually written from relevant subsidiary books is",
A: "debtors account",
B: "control account",
C: "trading account",
D: "creditors account",
answer: "A. Returns inward journal",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The difference in a trial balance total is posted to",
A: "imprest account",
B: "adjustment account",
C: "suspense account",
D: "trading account",
answer: "A. Debit note",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The accounting entries for the purchase of a van by a bookshop for cash are debit",
A: "motor vehicle account; credit cash account",
B: "purchases account; credit cash account",
C: "cash account; credit motor vehicle account",
D: "cash account; credit purchases account",
answer: "C. Drawings",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The double entry principle states that debit",
A: "the giver and credit the receiver",
B: "the receiver and credit the giver",
C: "income and credit expenses",
D: "capital and credit sales",
answer: "B. Depreciation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. An example of a contra entry transaction is",
A: "withdrawals from bank to cash till",
B: "withdrawals of goods from store",
C: "cash in transit",
D: "goods in transit",
answer: "B. Payable ledger",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The amount of capital expenditure for 2017 is",
A: "₦840,000",
B: "₦790,000",
C: "₦390,000",
D: "₦320,000",
answer: "C. Cash discount",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The amount of revenue expenditure is",
A: "₦840,000",
B: "₦790,000",
C: "₦390,000",
D: "₦320,000",
answer: "C. N80,028",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The accounting concept that demands that assets are recorded at their purchase price is",
A: "matching concept",
B: "historical cost concept",
C: "consistency concept",
D: "money measurement concept",
answer: "D. N4,212",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. A firm using FIFO method of valuation should not change to LIFO method until a change is deemed necessary according to the",
A: "consistency concept",
B: "materiality concept",
C: "periodicity concept",
D: "matching concept",
answer: "B. Commission",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The principle that separates the owners’ expenses from that of the business is",
A: "cost concept",
B: "business entity concept",
C: "accrual concept",
D: "matching concept",
answer: "A. Working capital",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The rent to be charged to the profit and loss account for the year is",
A: "GH₵3,000",
B: "GH₵2,400",
C: "GH₵2,200",
D: "GH₵1,400",
answer: "A. Trade creditors have been overpaid by GHc420",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The amount of rent prepaid is shown in the balance sheet as",
A: "fixed asset",
B: "current asset",
C: "current liability",
D: "long-term lability",
answer: "B. Accounts of individual customers and suppliers",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Income receivable on investment is treated in the balance sheet as",
A: "current liability",
B: "long-term liability",
C: "current assets",
D: "fixed assets",
answer: "B. Reduction in provision for doubtful debts",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Provision for doubtful debt is made in order to",
A: "write off bad debts",
B: "allow for possible bad debts",
C: "make a debtor pay",
D: "liquidate a debtor’s business",
answer: "B. Going concern concept",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. A reserve is an amount",
A: "set out of profit for an estimated liability",
B: "of loss from trading activities",
C: "of profit made by a manufacturing firm",
D: "set aside out of profit for specific purpose",
answer: "C. Comparability of accounting records",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The method of providing for depreciation which ensures that annual charges are constant throughout the estimated useful life of the asset is",
A: "straight line method",
B: "reducing balance method",
C: "revaluation method",
D: "sum of the years’ digits method",
answer: "A. Realization concept",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The summation of raw materials cost, factory wages and direct expenses is",
A: "production cost",
B: "factory cost",
C: "prime cost",
D: "production overheads",
answer: "A. Opening stock + purchases – closing stock",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Manufacturing overheads are made up of",
A: "direct expenses",
B: "royalties",
C: "raw material cost",
D: "indirect cost",
answer: "C. Factory overheads",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The total of return inwards book is posted to",
A: "debit side of Debtors Control Account",
B: "debit side of Creditors Control Account",
C: "credit side of Debtors Control Account",
D: "credit side of Creditors Account",
answer: "C. Le90,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The balance on the Sales Ledger Control Account shows",
A: "outstanding debtors",
B: "outstanding creditors",
C: "payments by debtors",
D: "payments by creditors",
answer: "A. Le30,000 gross profit",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The personal accounts of creditors are found in the",
A: "general ledger",
B: "nominal ledger",
C: "purchases ledger",
D: "sales ledger",
answer: "B. Reserve",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The entry to be made when a debtor’s cheque is dishonoured is debit",
A: "debtors’ s account and credit cash account",
B: "bank account and credit debtor’s account",
C: "debtor’s account and credit bank account",
D: "cash account and credit bank account",
answer: "D. Depreciation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The opening creditors is D2,800, closing creditors D5,200, payment to creditors D4,200 and discount received D200. What is the amount of credit purchases?",
A: "D7,200",
B: "D6,800",
C: "D2,400",
D: "D2,000",
answer: "B. Sale of plant and machinery",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following is not an item in the Sales ledger Control Account?",
A: "Cheque received",
B: "Bills payable",
C: "Bills received",
D: "Cheque dishonoured",
answer: "D. Debited to the manufacturing account",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Incomplete records refer to a set of accounts that",
A: "is prepared at the beginning of the year",
B: "does not conform to double entry principle",
C: "show a net loss on operation",
D: "is not reconciled with the bank statement",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Credit sales and purchases are obtained from incomplete records by preparing",
A: "statement of affairs",
B: "accumulated fund",
C: "profit and loss account",
D: "control accounts",
answer: "C. GHc111,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The subscriptions figure to be transferred to the Income and Expenditure Account for the year ended December 31, 2016 is",
A: "Le5,600",
B: "Le5,300",
C: "Le5,200",
D: "Le5,000",
answer: "B. GHc94,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The subscriptions figure which will be shown as part of the current asset in the balance sheet as at 31/12/2016 is",
A: "Le750",
B: "Le450",
C: "Le300",
D: "Le150",
answer: "A. Trade debtors at the end of the year",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Subscriptions in arrears is treated in the balance sheet of a social club as a",
A: "fixed asset",
B: "current asset",
C: "current liability",
D: "long-term liability",
answer: "B. D370,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following is not a reason for termination of partnership?",
A: "Death of a partner",
B: "Bankruptcy of a partner",
C: "Net loss recorded during the year",
D: "Expiration of fixed term of business",
answer: "B. D230,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Where there is no partnership agreement, advances by any partner in excess of capital contribution shall attract interest at the rate of",
A: "20%",
B: "15%",
C: "10%",
D: "5%",
answer: "D. Accumulated fund",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The interest on capital debited to Appropriation Account is",
A: "D33,050",
B: "D32,500",
C: "D17,500",
D: "D15,000",
answer: "D. N1,650",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Jack’s share of profit is",
A: "D40,340",
B: "D24,248",
C: "D16,172",
D: "D8,086",
answer: "A. N2,640",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The Current Asset is",
A: "D1,950",
B: "D1,730",
C: "D1,650",
D: "D1,250",
answer: "C. Ordinary shareholders",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The working capital is",
A: "D1,350",
B: "D1,250",
C: "D1,030",
D: "D950",
answer: "D. Partners asset value appreciates",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The capital is",
A: "D7,950",
B: "D7,330",
C: "D7,250",
D: "D6,950",
answer: "B. N7,404",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following ratios measures the liquidity of a firm?",
A: "Gross profit percent",
B: "Acid test ratio",
C: "Debtors’ collection period",
D: "Net profit margin",
answer: "C. N4,936",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The amount received from a sale of a business is",
A: "share premium",
B: "goodwill",
C: "capital",
D: "purchase consideration",
answer: "C. Cash account; credit realization account",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. A public limited liability company is a business organization with",
A: "a maximum of fifty members",
B: "a minimum of three members",
C: "an unlimited number of members",
D: "at least five members",
answer: "C. Allotment",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The basis for apportioning rent of premises in a departmental account is",
A: "sales",
B: "turnover",
C: "floor area",
D: "purchases",
answer: "B. Debited to the income surplus account",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Which of the following is not a method of charging goods to branches?",
A: "Cost price",
B: "Fixed price",
C: "Selling price",
D: "Cost plus a percentage",
answer: "A. Floor space occupied by the department",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The accounting entries in the Head Office books when credit sales is made by the branch are debit",
A: "Stock Account, credit Branch Debtors Account",
B: "Debtors Account, credit Branch Stock Account",
C: "Adjustment Account, credit Branch Debtors Account",
D: "Stock Account, credit Branch Adjustment Account",
answer: "C. Branch stock account",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The accounts of local government are prepared on",
A: "Accrual basis",
B: "Materiality basis",
C: "Cash basis",
D: "Cost basis",
answer: "C. Le101,142",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. A source of revenue available to a local government is",
A: "property rates",
B: "value added tax",
C: "income tax",
D: "excise duties",
answer: "C. Le14,354",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Which of the following instruments is used to release funds before the approval of the Appropriation Bill?",
A: "Virement warrant",
B: "Provision general warrant",
C: "Reserved expenditure warrant",
D: "Contingency warrant",
answer: "A. Warrant",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. A situation whereby shares are issued at a price above their nominal value is an issue at",
A: "par",
B: "a discount",
C: "a premium",
D: "cost",
answer: "C. To be carried forward to the next fiscal year",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]